Samina Qazi

Contact: +92333-3416093

Email: saminaqazi25@gmail.com

Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/samina-qazi/



CAREER OBJECTIVE:

A conscientious professional 10 years of experience with commitment and devoted services in the field of management, administration, coordination, academia and social mobilization. A passion for delivery of top class service as desired and mindset of Organization. A superb attention to detailed and caring attitude. A dependable character, self-starter and respected manager with discretion, loyalty and personal responsibility. Now targeting to excel the career in challenging and promising organization.

CAREER PROFILE/SKILLS:

- Human Resources Generalist
- Management Training & Development
- Leadership Development & Assessment
- Job Task Analysis
- Organizational Development
- Management & Coordination
- Budgeting and financial Decisions
- Compensation & benefits
- Implementing Procedures and policies reform
- Curriculum Design, Development, Analysis & Research

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE:

Organization: Toyota Point Motors

Automobile company

Tenure: Mar 2018- Till Date
Designation: Manager HR

Responsibilities:



- Plan and coordinate an organization's workforce to best use employees' talents
- Training & Development
- Leave management
- Oversee an organization's recruitment, interview, selection, and hiring processes
- Handle staffing issues, such as mediating disputes and directing disciplinary procedures
- Oversee and manage a performance appraisal system that drives high performance for that reason we are working for activities of every department such as Sales, Admin, Parts, Services and other departments.
- Payroll Management
- Assess training needs to apply and monitor training programs.
- Report to management and provide decision support through HR metrics
- Develop and implement HR strategies and initiatives aligned with the overall business strategy
- Bridge management and employee relations by addressing demands, grievances or other issues after proper check & balance such as after approval of every requisition
- Link an organization's management with its employees
- Developing and administering human resources plans and procedures that relate to company personnel

- Planning, organizing, and controlling the activities and actions of the HR department
- Contributing to the development of HR department goals, objectives, and systems
- Implementing and revising a company's compensation program
- Creating and revising job descriptions
- Conducting annual salary surveys
- Developing, analyzing, and updating the company's salary budget
- Developing, analyzing and updating the company's evaluation program
- Developing, revising, and recommending personnel policies and procedures
- Maintaining and revising the company's handbook on policies and procedures
- Performing benefits administration
- Maintaining affirmative action programs
- Overseeing recruitment efforts for all personnel, including writing and placing job ads
- Conducting new employee orientations and employee relations counseling
- Overseeing exit interviews
- Maintaining department records and reports
- Participating in administrative staff meetings
- Maintaining company directory and other organizational charts
- · Recommending new policies, approaches, and procedures

Achievement:

- Best Trainer Award for trainings on professional Ethics, Conflict Management, Holistic Safety, Soft skills etc.
- Best Event organizer
- Employee attendance award

Organization: SZABIST ZABTech (ITVE)

Technical Vocational Eucational SYstem

Tenure: May 2015-May 2017

Designation: Principal / HR Head / QEC Head

SZARIST

Responsibilities:

- To ensure smooth and efficient running of institute
- To steer the campaign for admissions
- To Reruit, Planning, organizing, and controlling the activities and actions of the HR department
- To conduct seminars & meeting for parents and students and to introduce SZABIST ZABTech (iTVE) System
- To plan the courses and their academic calendar.
- To manage the academic discipline of the SZABIST ZABTech (iTVE)
- To supervise admission process
- To monitor academic standards
- To execute ZABTech Desk System smoothly and efficiently
- To device and enforce evaluation system at the end of each course
- To launch the marketing events to introduce the alumni to job market

- To supervise the financial affairs of the SZABIST ZABTech (iTVE)
- To prepare monthly, quarterly, annually academic and financial reports
- To organize monthly academic meeting with the faculty and get feedback
- To organize social events for students to participate and prove their creative skills
- To prepare events held at campus in writing to the directorate
- To ensure quality of teaching deduction of drop out ratio of students.
- To organize award ceremony every year for pass out students
- To support the selection process of Academic staff
- To act as Secretary to Management Committee
- Any other duty assigned by Director, SZABIST ZABTech (iTVE) from time to time.

Achievements:

- Certificate of Appreciation by District Government for the brilliant work for youth development
- Certificate of appreciation by District Government for working beyond expectation for the services in vicinity
 of district

Organization: Excellence Education System

(Educational System for Preprimary to Higher secondary Education)

Tenure: July 2013 – April 2015

Designation: Principal

Responsibilities:

- Principal had to administer student's personnel program from primary to college sections and counsels disciplines students, performing any combination of following tasks.
- Formulate student personnel policies like code of ethics
- Plan to supervise school students activity programs
- Monitoring of securities of school and coordinates teacher supervision of areas
- Maintain record of all teachers and students
- Admission campaign/
- Recruitment process
- Teachers evaluation
- Teachers trainings
- Arranging PTM with conuselling

Organization: The Educators (A Beacon House System)

(Educational System for Preprimary to Higher secondary Education)

Tenure: Aug 2012 – June 2013

Designation: Principal

THE EDUCATORS

Organization: Hayat Girls Higher Scondaey School

(Educational System for Preprimary to Higher secondary Education)

Tenure: April 2010 – Aug 2012

Designation: Vice Principal

Organization: NUML University
Tenure: Feb 2011- 2016

Designation: Visiting Faculty (Part Time)





ACADEMIC EDUCATION:

DEGREE/CERTIFICATION	EXAMINING BODY:	YEAR
MBA HR	Allama Iqbal OpenUniversity	2012
Master's in Education (M.Ed)	University of Sindh Jamshoro, SIndh Pakistan	2019
Master In Arts (Economics)	University of Sindh Jamshoro, SIndh Pakistan	2009
Bachelor in Law LLB	University of Sindh Jamshoro, SIndh Pakistan	2016

CERTIFICATION/ ADDITIONAL SKILLS:

National Assessor Reg # CBA/2019/854 http://www.npess.pk/nvqf/view_assessor.php

Master trainer Trained trainer by ITC ILO, GIZ

O MS Office All versions, sp. MS Word, MS Power Point and MS Excel

MS Excel
 MS Formulae, Reports Automation, Macros, Presentations w.r.t. Analysis

Certification
 Certificate in SPSS

o Certification Certificate of Entrepreneurship from HEC

TRAININGS & WORKSHOPS:

Trainings Conducted:

- Training for HRD Human Rights defender in Karachi for five days by DCHD
- Training for Psycho Social Security for human rights defender in khi for 4 days.
- One day training of DMC for data collection by GIZ in Isalamabad
- National Assessor Training by GIz
- 10 Days Training on KAB (Know About Business) at SZABIST
- 2 Days Hands on workshop on SEO at ITC Auto Bhan Road
- 2 days training on Digital media marketing at ITC Auto Bhan Road
- 1 day training on Vocational education in Talhar
- 7days training on vocational education different organizations of BADIN
- 3 days training obn BASICs of Educational Management in AFAQ for Principals & Directors
- 8 days training on Adult Literacy in IRM

Achievements/Recognition/Honors

- Master Trainer
- Shield of Appreciation on Academic Competition 2012, Board of Intermediate & Scondary Education Hyderabad, Sindh
- Judge for NAVTTC Skill Competition
- Assessor for NAVTTC Phase III Batch II final Examinations For beautician & Fashion Designing Trades.
- Letter of commendation from Deputy commissioner Tando Mohammad Khan for best performance in different social events for youth reformation.
- ILO "KAB (Know About Business)" Certified Trainer.
- HEC certified for Essential of Entrepreneurship skills.
- Attended many seminars as guest speaker and awarded many shields and certificates.
- Best Officer for the year Award in Hayat Girls College in July 2011
- Guest Speaker on Telecommunication in Different seminars.

- BISE Awarded Shield for Organizing Inter Collegiate Spelling Bee first ever in Hyderabad (and recruited as a member of BISE organizer for spelling bee) 2010.
- Shield and Medal for securing First Position in Table Tennis at Inter Class Sports 1995-96.
- Medal for securing Second Position in Table Tennis (Women) Champion Ship at Annual Sports 1996
- Medal for securing Second Position in Table Tennis (Women) Champion Ship at Annual Sports 1997.
- First Position in Organizing Technical Exhibition on occasion of Silver Jubilee week celebration of Chemical Engineering Department of MUET, Jamshoro, 1996.
- Best performance in extracurricular activities Just like Drama, Comparing & Speech.
- Certificate of Training in Essential of Entrepreneurship from Higher Education Commission.
- The Best Officer on the Occasion of PASSING-OUT CEREMONY for class XII, 2011 from Hayat Girls Higher Secondary School.
- Guest Speaker on Importance of Leadership Skills from Young Social Reformers.
- Shield of Appreciation on Academic Competition 2011, Board of Intermediate & Secondary Education Hyderabad, Sindh.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Father's Name : Qazi Rashid Hassan

 Date of Birth
 : 25-10-1982

 Driving License
 : CA5153562

REFERENCE:

Reference will be furnished on demand.